Jackson: It made the cut
Tyler: I'm imagining Chris showing up at like a modern-day Ellis Island with like a single bag and a
Tyler: Mechanical keyboard that's split and ergonomic and he's like I would like to enter this country
Tyler: Fable is war profiteering. Okay, this is this is definitely against the anthropic toss
Chris: Bro like whoa burp. We got a perp. We got a perp
Chris: Okay, let's go. We are already underwater
Chris: Only three cents. Okay. All right
Jackson: Three two one
Jackson: All right, welcome to our first digital podcast you're on the permanent under pod with Jackson cook
Chris: I think your next Tyler
Chris: Co-host Tyler here that that co-host Chris
Jackson: and
Jackson: It's a beautiful day. I actually am in
Jackson: Georgia right now in the in the countryside
Jackson: Sweating my face off
Jackson: Where are you guys at? What's what's going on?
Jackson: I'm at home
Tyler: Yeah, you know, you might recognize this room from from episode two different orientation, but same room
Chris: I'm I'm in a brand new room that I think I've never been in on the pod and like, you know behind the scenes
Chris: there's like a very
Chris: Insane kind of like gamer adjacent setup here that we were all laughing at earlier. So
Jackson: I'm okay. Would it be trivial for you to show us your gamer setup and then explain your gamer thumb?
Chris: you know, I think like maybe we can overlay the picture or you know, the
Chris: But yeah, it's
Chris: Hopefully the audio quality is good and you promised us you'd be wearing your
Jackson: Your brace for your gamer thumb. Do you have it? It's ready to hot on
Chris: I so I had to take it off because and you'll see from the picture
Chris: I have this like insane keyboard setup and I don't have the thumb mobility with the brace to hit alt so I can tap
Chris: So maybe that's what did it, you know, I don't know
Jackson: Dude, that's some wind windows stuff. He said alt. There is no alt command on the
Tyler: Okay, this man doesn't have a Mac keyboard. Come on
Chris: Sorry, when does the is the gamer operating system? Yeah
Tyler: It's on team, but I like how you're you're like
Tyler: Well, I have gamer thumb and I'm supposed to wear this brace
Tyler: But since the brace isn't compatible with my ridiculous keyboard that is hurting me and giving me gamer thumb
Tyler: therefore I'll take it off so that I can continue mashing my thumb into the spacebar like this is you like
Jackson: This is why you have gamer thumb Chris. Do you've seen a picture of it? Like would you give this up? It's primo
Tyler: Yeah, I mean your your productivity is probably going to go down at least
Tyler: 20% if you just had a normie keyboard and your brace on so I can understand
Chris: Right, it's for the cause. Yeah, gotta stay. Yeah
Jackson: It's a good thing. We're doing this actually because I think we just diagnosed it Chris if you have to reach
Jackson: Yeah, and you do command I do command all the time yeah, I do this might be it
Chris: I'm I'm not getting rid of the keyboard. Like my thumb is just gonna be like this forever
Tyler: Did you bring your keyboard with you when you immigrated from Australia I
Chris: Did you did I brought one suitcase and like this to go goes in it
Chris: Yeah
Tyler: It's sentimental at this point. I'm imagining Chris showing up at like a modern-day Ellis Island with like a single bag and a
Tyler: Mechanical keyboard that's split and ergonomic and he's like I would like to to enter this country
Chris: Now you have to bring the tools of your trade, you know when you're immigrating anyway, anyway, I think like it's very important
Jackson: They're probably welcoming you in with their open arms productive member of society, but who knows?
Jackson: All right. So we're gonna go into our first segment. That is
Jackson: Totally insane. So you may remember from the last episode that Tyler
Jackson: Did like an AI segment of us explaining open USD with voices
Jackson: But now we've got it with improved voices and with the video
Jackson: So get ready. Note. This is AI generated content. This is not us and
Jackson: Even when it's us, these are our opinions and do not reflect our employers opinions
Jackson: So without further ado check out this beautiful video that Tyler made
Jackson: explaining Venice AI
AI Hosts: Speedround here's the news
AI Hosts: Venice AI the quote-unquote private uncensored chat GPT raised 65 million at a billion dollar
AI Hosts: Valuation last Tuesday led by dragonfly. It's run by arid voorhees certified crypto elder and they're claiming 3 million users and profitability
AI Hosts: Both of which I choose to believe because I'm a nice person Tyler. You've been doing angry research all week
AI Hosts: I could feel it through the group chat smoke or fire
AI Hosts: Smoke like 90 percent smoke. Okay, so here's the thing
AI Hosts: Everyone should understand about Venice by default your prompt goes through their proxy to some GPU provider in plain text and the entire
AI Hosts: Privacy model is that Venice pinky promises not to write it down their own website. This is real
AI Hosts: I'm not making this up describes the default mode as quote provider sees and likely saves your prompt
AI Hosts: Incredible sentence to put on your own privacy page. That's like a restaurant menu that says the chef sees and likely leaks your food
AI Hosts: right and
AI Hosts: The reason this makes me insane is that the credible version of this product exists
AI Hosts: There are providers doing inference inside a trusted execution environment the chip itself proves with an attestation
AI Hosts: That it's running the code you expect and nobody can see inside not even the operator
AI Hosts: That's the math version of privacy Venice's default is the vibes version. It's trust. Don't verify from crypto people
AI Hosts: Trust don't verify. Did you cross stitch that onto a pillow before the show or it's going on the thumbnail. I don't make the rules
AI Hosts: Okay, so expert corner because I did the boring reading and it's slightly more annoying than Tyler wants it to be Venice did ship
AI Hosts: The real thing this year is now a TEA mode and an end-to-end encrypted mode actual hardware enclaves remote attestation
AI Hosts: run with near AI cloud and father
AI Hosts: Cryptographically legit as far as I can tell the catch is those are opt-in tears
AI Hosts: So the privacy company added privacy in year two as a premium mode, which tells you exactly what the other three million people are on
AI Hosts: They're on the provider sees and likely saves your prompt plan
AI Hosts: Those poor uncensored prompts dude somewhere. There's a GPU in a warehouse that knows everything about three million people's worst 2 a.m. Questions
AI Hosts: It knows about your tax question Jackson
AI Hosts: My tax question was on fable and fable would never fable respects me
AI Hosts: Fable was literally confiscated by the federal government for three weeks and you waited outside like a dog at a vet
AI Hosts: Okay, so maybe I'm not the objective voice on this segment the default my thing is basically incognito my privacy by the way
AI Hosts: It's private from your wife
AI Hosts: It is not private from the infrastructure and look I'll give Venice the concession because someone has to the demand is real the marketing worked
AI Hosts: 3 million people now believe AI privacy is a thing they should want smoke matters smoke is how normal people find the fire
AI Hosts: Sure, but then there's the token. They minted a token vvv where staking it gets you inference, which I'll do the incentive read in one sentence
AI Hosts: It's a way to get paid like a crypto project while shipping a product with the margins of a proxy server
AI Hosts: And the part that actually gets me is I think Voorhees believes all of it
AI Hosts: Like this is a true believer riding the hype train he built which is worse than cynical cynics take profits and leave
AI Hosts: believers at a series a
AI Hosts: True believers make the best exit liquidity. That's the whole history about industry mate
AI Hosts: Okay, 30-second recap because I contain 40 lines of multitudes
AI Hosts: And this is what they're for Venice real demand real fundraise privacy. That was a pinky promise until this year
AI Hosts: actual cryptographic privacy now available as a paid add-on and a token that's either the future of compute or
AI Hosts: securities lawsuit with staking rewards
AI Hosts: Final one-liners Chris
AI Hosts: Venice is the only company where we finally added the thing our name means counts as a product launch team open weights team actual enclaves team
AI Hosts: Bitcoin in that order if your privacy model fits in a policy doc
AI Hosts: It's a promise if it fits in an attestation
AI Hosts: It's a fact Venice sells promises and rents facts from falla
AI Hosts: That's the segment and I'd sell both of your souls for one more week of fable access which the clone listening to this already knows
AI Hosts: Up next purple fortune fable picks the trade Pico's health care rides on it. Let's go
Jackson: boom
Jackson: Now we're back
Jackson: guys
Jackson: First of all, what do you think of the video? And what do you think of the AI discussion on Venice AI?
Chris: Are we are we rolling the the creepy video?
Jackson: It already ran. It just ran. Yeah, you have to pretend like we just watched it and that it does not yet exist
Chris: Happens in real life canonically
Chris: Okay
Chris: That's that's a crazy video
Chris: He's literally me
Chris: No, I think like with this one for me at least the takes are
Chris: Again, like surprisingly spot-on, but I'm like I'm not a Venice
Chris: expert
Chris: So I like, you know, I don't have like the sharpest takes here
Tyler: But I feel like the AI Chris was way more confident and his expertise in his takes and the real life Chris
Tyler: Who is more humble and?
Tyler: hedging
Chris: Yeah, he definitely went for the throat
Chris: But I think like the the drift the drift of it was like was bang on like
Chris: Yeah, but I don't know. I know Tyler you had some like very
Chris: down-the-line opinions on this one
Tyler: In the video or at IRL. I mean, I think it helped that I made the video and the audio and all that and so
Tyler: I don't know. I think it might have seeded with some of my takes
Tyler: IRL
Tyler: but I mean first off I feel like the
Tyler: voice
Tyler: Simulation is way better than it was last week because we had that podcast at Presidio Bitcoin with like elite
Tyler: Microphones and elite podcasting setup. So now we have all this training data
Tyler: And so this week when it generated our voices they were like pretty pretty point on and then
Tyler: Same with the takes. I mean, I feel like the AI is distilling our souls week by week
Tyler: Getting more and more accurate and I feel like there's a little bit of our personalities even in the AI simulation
Jackson: but
Tyler: Yeah, I mean I think that the
Tyler: AI Tyler's take is pretty much what my take is with Venice
Tyler: Which is it's a cool concept. I like the idea of private AI
Tyler: But I feel like they're not doing it
Tyler: really well
Tyler: because they're
Tyler: You know free tier is basically the worst of both worlds. It's we collect your data. I don't even know if they commit to
Tyler: Not keeping logs. It says on their website
Tyler: like basically if you have the free tier we can like see all your sessions and all your queries and
Tyler: My guess is that like 90% of the people that come to them for like the private AI brand aren't reading the fine print
Tyler: and they're just using the free tier and if it's me, I would much rather have my
Tyler: Activity be housed in something like chat GBT or Claude
Tyler: because I trust those teams to be way more competent and also those teams I feel like I
Tyler: Have to be very careful with their privacy because they have have these like, you know trillion dollar businesses
Tyler: Whereas I don't want to give my like financial history to Eric Voorhees and Venice AI
Tyler: Like I don't know who the heck is buying that company. I don't know if they're technically competent and
Tyler: For all I know they can just like exit scam the whole thing and sell my data or something like that
Tyler: So yeah, I think if you use it in the higher tier where you have the end-to-end encryption and the TE guarantees
Tyler: Then it seems like a great product that probably gives you the privacy that you want
Tyler: But also they're not exclusively the people that are offering that like there are multiple other providers that offer
Tyler: The same experience one is maple AI and they don't need a token to do it
Tyler: You just pay them a subscription. You can do it in Bitcoin. You can pay them in dollars
Tyler: You don't need a token. I think the token is completely
Tyler: something that is just stitched on and kind of like a
Tyler: Attempt to ride the AI hype in a way that I think Eric for ease is extremely adept at
Tyler: You know making himself a lot of money using crypto tokens and riding the right hype wave in the right cycle
Tyler: So that's my those are my takes long ran
Jackson: Mr. Voorhees has been called out directly
Chris: Yeah, I mean I so I mean BBV stands for Voorhees for he's Voorhees actually the token
Chris: That's a joke. It doesn't it doesn't
Chris: But I think like, you know, maybe for the listeners a little bit of context on Voorhees
Chris: He started shapeshift, which was one of the first KYC lists crypto exchanges
Tyler: Well, even before that he was he bought Satoshi dice, which was like one of the first gambling businesses on Bitcoin and
Tyler: so he he was like a super early Bitcoin or because he's like a really hardcore libertarian and
Tyler: Early on there was a service called Satoshi dice where you would send a little bit of Bitcoin into this service to an address
Tyler: and then based on the
Tyler: hash of the next block
Tyler: It would basically send you either back your money double or it would keep the money
Tyler: And so it was like basically just doing like all or nothing bet and this got super popular in early Bitcoin like I don't know
Tyler: 2011 2013 whatever it at one point it was a majority of all block space was being used for Satoshi dice and
Tyler: He like swooped in and bought this business from the person who started it like at its peak
Tyler: made a bunch of money off of Satoshi dice and I think he shut it down because it was obviously like
Tyler: running a
Tyler: gambling outfit and I my understanding is that he took the winnings from Satoshi dice and
Tyler: Rolled it into shapeshift, which was like the next thing that he did that was incredibly lucrative. Maybe Chris you can pick it up from there
Chris: Yeah, I mean shapeshift is you know, it's exactly what I said
Chris: Sort of like not really decentralized cross-chain crypto exchange that was KYC lists
Chris: I think it unwound for the exact reasons that you would imagine with a service like that
Chris: Like if you're doing that and you don't have like a defensible case that you, you know, can't provide KYC
Tyler: I think you know you have to think he had like criminal charges filed against him for operating shapeshift and then he settled them
Tyler: But like shift was very popular back in the 2017 bull run. Yeah, I was a big
Tyler: Shapeshift experiencer, I never did trades on it though. It was it
Chris: sure, it was a it was a great product and sort of a protocol that I built in a past life was
Chris: Trying to emulate that experience, right? Like I think it had like this massive
Chris: Effect on the industry whether whether it was done, you know in genuineness or not
Chris: Yeah, I think like a lot of people were
Chris: Inspired by it. I would like to I didn't know about Satoshi dice and I just want to like as a quicker side
Chris: Say that like that's like
Chris: That's like the RuneScape doubling money scam that he was doing
Chris: I don't I like some of our listeners will know what that is. That's insane. That's crazy
Jackson: Wow, yeah for I mean for better or worse it seems like mr. Voorhees is the face of this company
Jackson: I'm curious for you guys that have been in the the crypto space for a long time
Jackson: What is like the community sentiment? Is he a rug puller or what? I would say he's a rug puller
Tyler: I think he's actually a very straightforward person. Like I don't think he ever lies or like over promises
Tyler: but I think he's just super adept at kind of like
Tyler: Being in the right place at the right time and I actually think he has very strong belief system and crypto ideals
Tyler: And so I do think that he tries to do things the right way
Tyler: Although I think in this case with Venice, I think that the product probably
Tyler: Isn't quite as strong as maybe the marketing and maybe it gets there but I think historically I've actually had a lot of respect
Tyler: For him and I don't think poorly of him necessarily
Tyler: But I that doesn't mean that I would want to like invest in a token that he is
Tyler: putting out in the world because I think that he's
Tyler: You know, he's doing that for a reason. He's one of those people that like he believes that if you as an adult
Tyler: you know enter into any kind of consenting financial transaction and that's on you and if that consenting financial transaction is that you buy his
Tyler: Token and get like basically give him money and you get nothing in return
Tyler: Then that's like, you know, there's nothing wrong with that because you can set to do it. So
Chris: Right you consented to having your money maybe doubled or maybe they log off take it all. Yeah, that's how it is
Jackson: Then the clothes out the for he is
Jackson: Yeah, we don't hate you man. We respect you and if you ever want to come talk
Jackson: You know, let us know what's next because we'd love to join you on your next lucrative venture
Jackson: second question for me is you know, this Venice AI seems like a
Jackson: Pathway for like people who want to have private AI whether or not it works
Jackson: You know perfectly out of the box or for free people that want to use AI privately
Jackson: They use Venice AI. What are some like alternatives? Like what is something where you can kind of invest some money and guarantee your privacy
Jackson: like
Jackson: For example running local models. What is the viability of running local models instead of using something like Venice AI?
Chris: So I I I want to out myself as like a total scrub here cuz like before the podcast
Chris: I was like, can't you just like buy a 3090 and just like run it up crazy style on GLM and
Chris: Jackson and Tyler who you know actually have like some kind of chops here. Well, I do know there's no way like it's impossible
Chris: Like you have to pay 40 grand
Chris: like just to just to start
Chris: being able to run some of those more like bleeding-edge open source models, so
Chris: I mean that that argument is out the window, right? Like there's it's just not cost efficient to be
Chris: You know spending all of this money on GPUs and and having your own farm to run some of these open source models
Chris: You know at the at the right hand end of the curve
Chris: Just for various reasons. So I was totally off on that one
Tyler: Jackson I feel like you're our local model expert
Tyler: You're the person who actually runs local models on your laptop and you compare them to cloud models, right?
Jackson: Yeah, yeah Quinn three and GLM 4.7 are the only two that I've run on like a standard issues and
Tyler: Like not a special computer like a high-end Mac book, but just a Mac book, right?
Jackson: Yeah, I've run them on both an M
Jackson: 2 and an M 5
Jackson: This is like an M 5 max computer and it makes my computer hot and the models are not great
Chris: That M 5 max is like 10 grand now, right? Like that's Todd. That's top spec
Jackson: Don't tell anybody my computer is 10 grand. But yes, it's 10 grand
Chris: So like it's not like you it's not it's not a toaster that you're yeah
Tyler: I guess pitching it is a normal Mac and it when it's a five-figure piece of computing equipment is a little underselling it
Chris: Yeah, and it has that Apple unified memory. So like it's one of the better place chips to run these models as well, right?
Jackson: Yeah, exactly. So I
Jackson: Don't know. I mean if you do want private AI
Jackson: Usage and you want it to be affordable then maybe just paying businesses is the way to do it
Jackson: rather than investing in
Jackson: More hardware than a 10 grand laptop
Tyler: Yeah
Chris: Well, maybe yeah, there's other services too
Tyler: I mean use Venice if you are a VVV holder and you want to pump your own bags
Tyler: Yeah, just don't use the free tier currently
Tyler: and then other services that I'm aware of our maple AI and
Tyler: I think tinfoil AI and my guess is that they all use the same infrastructure provider under the hood and they're just kind of like
Tyler: An app or a wrapper on top of that
Tyler: But I think they provide you with similar assurances and then it's just which interface you like better
Tyler: They provide you with the same assurances same underlying models
Tyler: But yeah, I don't think it's feasible to run
Tyler: like the best open models on
Tyler: consumer hardware
Tyler: This one thing that I saw and I shared with Chris before the pod was like if you want to run GLM 5 2
Tyler: Which is considered the best open model right now
Tyler: Like the price of entry is like forty to fifty thousand dollars worth of GPUs
Tyler: and then you have to like put them together into this like hardcore home computing rack and then
Tyler: Yeah, you then you have like a leaf blower and your living room giving you
Tyler: Intelligence that is worse than the intelligence that you can get for a $20 cloud subscription
Tyler: So I feel like it's the local
Tyler: Like Citadel quality AI is a little bit of a pipe dream right now
Tyler: Maybe eventually the models compress down to where you get like today's frontier of intelligence running on Jackson's MacBook
Tyler: Like I don't know if you extrapolate out the trends. Maybe you get there eventually
Tyler: But I feel like the frontier is always gonna have like extreme hardware requirements and for me, I would rather just pay a subscription
Tyler: and either do like the
Tyler: You know lay my soul out to anthropic and just let them harvest my data in return for you know, the
Tyler: the highest intelligence out there that is fable or
Tyler: One of these, you know private subscription providers where you have a similar model
Tyler: But you have those guarantees seems like a better trade-off balance to me than spending forty fifty thousand dollars on hardware
Tyler: that may or may not be relevant within a few years and
Tyler: yeah, but before the pot I was we had this thought experiment which was like if
Tyler: Somebody came up to you and offered you like four years ago. Like if I was like Jackson, I
Tyler: Can give you a box and in this box?
Tyler: there's gonna live a software engineer that lives in this box in your house and
Tyler: This software engineer will work for you 24/7 and is really good at coding
Tyler: Never complains and just works all the time like a dog
Tyler: And I can offer this to you for $50,000
Tyler: Would you buy that box and you'd be like hell?
Tyler: Yeah, I'd buy that box because it can make me do my job that pays me more than $50,000 like you have more time to
Tyler: record podcasts and play tennis and
Tyler: All that stuff so it's kind of crazy like you know, that would be like an insane deal and concept a couple years ago
Tyler: But now we're just like why would you do that?
Tyler: You can just pay like $100 and get that, you know in just in the fatigue able software
Tyler: I try in a box, but the box just happens to be in the cloud
Chris: That trade is insane because I think it's not just that we've gone from like would you have a 50 grand software engineer?
Chris: Who does whatever you want?
Chris: It's like now the trade is like I'm willing to give away like every facet of my mortal soul for like a slightly better version of that
Chris: Like there's there's a there's a single digit percent chance
Chris: There is like a Tyler soul MD on an entropic server somewhere coming up with like some cracked payment method right now
Chris: I just like ripping that ripping that out of you, dude. It's probably just thinking of really sick
Jackson: Podcast segments insane bones. Yeah
Jackson: Yeah, I agree my AI simp
Jackson: You know Jackson would also agree as you guys if you guys listen to the
Jackson: To the stupid transcript. I'm like a major be a point where you're just like
Tyler: Anyways for me to use like you'll be like I never need to go past like Opus
Tyler: 48 like Opus 48 is just like all the intelligence I need and even though there's like, you know fable
Tyler: Nine out there. You're like, yeah, I don't need that. It's too expensive
Tyler: whatever
Jackson: Not if it runs whenever I want it to but honestly today and yesterday fable has been like
Jackson: Blocking me for a bunch of reasons
Jackson: So I've been using lower tier models just because I don't want to be slowed down
Tyler: Are you getting like rate limited or being naughty blocks?
Jackson: Yeah, I'm getting both too both and it's like now I shouldn't even use this this is wasting my time
Chris: Yeah, it won't even like audit don't ever use the word audit. That's my advice
Chris: that's not a good world that we work into it like does not like
Tyler: Doing anything with Bitcoin or cryptography. It's like, ooh, that's scary
Jackson: No, yeah, but
Jackson: Quick side note. I was doing the maximum quality recording and it's like two gigs a minute and I'm scared
Jackson: That's gonna go. I'm gonna end this one and start another one. Hold up Chris new I
Chris: Did I knew yeah, I
Tyler: Checked Chris's engineer about it makes assumptions and then like plans out for cases and
Tyler: Jackson is a YOLO
Chris: engineer
Chris: Yeah, I'm a trap doors behind trap those guy give me a clap one two three
Jackson: Sorry, that was a total mistake on my sound terrible now what happened to you
Tyler: Do I really know?
Jackson: Okay
Chris: I'm back from like burning - you know a gig every two minutes
Jackson: All right. Well as a I promised it's time to get in a perp of fortune and let's use fable
Jackson: Please fable don't rate limit us Chris. Take it away
Chris: Okay, so I gave fable out from 12 ahead of time anticipating the rate limiting and guardrails. I did get guardrailed one time but
Chris: You know engineer that I am found a way around it
Chris: So maybe I'll just read out fable's thesis and then we can we can run purple fortune do it
Chris: Okay, so same prompt as last time which just describes, you know what I wanted to do and you know where it can trade so
Chris: Here it says research done. Here's the thesis purple fortune the pic long XYZ CL, which is
Chris: WTI crude 20x leverage $100 margin $2,000 notional the story
Chris: Well, you know, I think we all know what the story here is and I'll condense it but basically
Chris: Iran is back and
Tyler: Fable thinks that WTA was war profiteering. Okay, this is this is definitely against the
Chris: Bro get it fable
Chris: Do I think I jailbroke him
Chris: Sorry, he he says there's like risk
Chris: He says that there is a runner-up for he says if you want maximum degeneracy for the pod
Chris: to short XYZ S&P 500 at 50x leverage
Chris: Which is I think a negative externality of the same XYZ
Jackson: 500
Chris: Isn't there a company with that? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, so X I
Chris: I'm not aware of
Chris: But I think you know, it was it was quite adamant that it wants to go
Chris: Long on crew so I think I'm just gonna say let's let's send it long. Yeah, and we also should should note
Jackson: We never gave you guys an update on the DRAM the dram
Jackson: but we got licked Chris's hundred dollars got burned into the
Jackson: pockets of hyper liquid or be pardon me of
Jackson: per offer
Jackson: That cats out of the bag, I'm sorry
Chris: So
Jackson: That happened like hours after the podcast and I was able to send
Jackson: successfully a hundred USDC on Arbitrum to Chris to fund this one, so
Tyler: Oil like the Department of Defense uses anthropic to plan like military operations
Tyler: do you think the clods are coordinating and it's like one Claude is aware like the
Tyler: Classified Claude that's in the Department of Defense data center is passing PII to the Claude that Chris is running and was like
Tyler: Do this insider trade, bro? I
Chris: Mean I think if you can infer the do these questions
Chris: You can probably get like reasonable Claude responses and then just like you know assume that they've said make their mistakes and then trade on that
Chris: Information, you know, that's that's a vector. Is it material non-public information?
Tyler: I mean Claude can derive it if anyone has access to a Claude, you know
Chris: Campy that's a good question. I wonder I think we need a legal guy on the pod
Jackson: We definitely don't I wonder if anyone's tried to like get data from other companies that use like Claude or anthropic
Jackson: You know like we are like you don't even have to work at a company. You're like a dude in a basement and you're like
Jackson: Hey, what is
Jackson: Nike working on right now Nike uses anthropic and anthropic's like scraping their data
Tyler: I wonder if you can see can like outbreak Claude to like hack into the other
Tyler: The logs for the other cloths. I'm gonna assume that that's not possible. I think it would I hope that's not possible
Jackson: If anything is
Jackson: We've seen it's like they are pretty jailbreakable, right? Yeah, but like only for stuff that probably was within there
Tyler: like weights
Tyler: Basically, like you can ask it you can maybe jailbreak it to to access knowledge
Tyler: That's in the weights that is forbidden knowledge or to get it to take some action with a tool it has access to but it
Tyler: can't like
Tyler: Magically conjure up data from a thing that it is like completely
Tyler: firewalled from I
Jackson: Guess I'm suggesting that it's ingested this data and put it into the weights and that's like the hidden data
Tyler: Yeah, well that's a big thing with like enterprise agreements with these companies is that
Tyler: They don't want like your company's internal code base to become trading data
Tyler: For for these models because then you could conceivably like have it just regurgitate your code to somebody else
Tyler: And so I think they are extremely careful about that
Jackson: Okay, I guess they may make no mistakes
Jackson: Anyways, you two, please don't ban us for talking about like hacking into Nike Nike's infrastructure. I'm sure it's not that interesting anyway, so
Jackson: Where's what's going on with the purple fortune it's cooking
Chris: Yeah, he's he's cooking dude. He just like I saw
Chris: Fables been rate-limited. So I've had to downgrade to Opus to actually place the trade and it's like
Chris: Gotta look up the hyper liquid docks, you know, he's like a little bit
Tyler: He's fables don't my cousin like let's be like a skillet like ready to give a shot like as I consult the docks every purple fortune
Chris: So I thought I had it in context that's the thing and I was like, I don't need a skill MDA
Chris: But Opus finds new ways to disappoint me
Jackson: Yeah, I tried using sonnet the other day
Jackson: Just like out of curiosity because it's one of the five that pop up when you type slash and it just asked me questions
Jackson: And I'm like, man, I'm done with this even with dangerously skip permissions. It just keeps asking me questions
Jackson: I need a smarter more assumption leaning model. I agency model
Chris: Maybe we should move on to another segment and just let Opus cook waiting for the optimal entry point
Tyler: I somehow like worse than last time opportunity moment thing interesting thing. So just a
Jackson: To preview it Chris wrote a really sexy
Jackson: blog post like two or three weeks ago about how like not all stable coins are the same and they kind of
Jackson: Depends on which chain the stable coin is on and like some of that might not make sense to you guys
Jackson: So maybe Chris you can start by explaining like what are the assets and then like what does it mean for it to be?
Jackson: Locked into a certain ecosystem or chain and to go from there
Chris: Yeah, totally so I mean like I think everybody knows about stable coin deep eggs
Chris: It's like kind of like one of the most fun things about stable coins
Chris: So for the uninitiated a deep egg is just when a stable coin which is supposed to be worth a dollar
Chris: Goes either over or under it by some white margin
Chris: So the reason that this normally happens and has historically happened is because the issuing institution of the stable coin
Chris: like something has either happened to their deposits or
Chris: like people have like lost faith in
Chris: Sort of their ability to redeem the stable coin for for one dollar for whatever reason so like Silvergate
Chris: Sorry, SVP with USDC. There was like questions about the collateral
Chris: It's happened to tether a couple of times for like, you know
Chris: Reasons similar to that where there were questions about whether the deposits were verified or even existed
Chris: So, I mean that's like a really well trodden class of stable coin deep egg
Chris: But what I think I think there's like another class of
Chris: pricing action for stable coins that people haven't really thought about too much yet because
Chris: Up until this point all of the stable coins have been concentrated on a couple of chains
Chris: Right like Solana, Ethereum a couple of L2s, but even between those chains
Chris: You know stable coins are even the same stable coin is valued differently and different stable coins are
Chris: valued way differently, so
Chris: For example, you know on base like tether normally trades a couple of bits off par
Chris: So instead of trading at one dollar, it will trade at ninety nine point nine nine eight or nine nine nine eight
Chris: Nine cents or something right? So just a couple of bits away
Chris: But sort of my hypothesis here is that like this could get way crazier
Chris: so like if you imagine, you know a world where there's
Chris: tempo arc
Chris: You know bass gets more volume Robin Hood chain and the issuers
Chris: Have their stable coins issued across all of these chains
Chris: there's so much more potential for drift and I think the drift is contingent on how quickly market makers can rebalance between these chains, so
Chris: Something that I did a couple of weeks at weekends ago as I set up price feeds
Chris: across all of these chains
Chris: Just to see like how big the Delta is already and and for example on base tether is is trading eight bips
Chris: Below every other chain and I assume it's just because the the gates between
Chris: Base and other chains for tether are not great like there's fees to get between them
Chris: And of course that changes the price of the asset on base versus versus other chains
Chris: And yeah, I just I think like, you know stable. Do you think it's because?
Tyler: Like USDC is the preferred stable coin on base and so there's just like persistent
Tyler: Selling pressure of tether to get into USDC to make other trades totally
Chris: I think it's I think it's a combination of liquidity and risk, right?
Chris: It's like how much liquidity how easy is it to move liquidity between these chains and how much is already there?
Chris: And what's the risk of me holding this asset?
Chris: Both like in general and like where the venue where I'm holding it
Chris: So, yeah, I think like I
Chris: Think this is gonna be like a real user experience problem for people. I think it only gets worse from here
Chris: Unfortunately, you know, depending on how issues want to deal with it
Chris: but yeah, just I think like something to watch out for something for people to think about when they're trying to
Chris: You know, just trying to buy their burrito a dollar is not a dollar
Jackson: Yeah, how easy is it to get like
Jackson: If I want to get a USDC
Jackson: from some chain and
Jackson: Turn it into like a US dollar. What would you do?
Jackson: And like would they actually what do they do about the fractions of the cent? Do you just lose that to the
Jackson: to the vendor
Chris: Right so I as an individual what would I yeah or
Chris: So me as an individual, I don't have and I think like we touched on this last episode
Chris: I don't have access to an institutional mint and burn desk. So it's not like I can go to
Chris: Circle and be like hey
Chris: Like give me a dollar over wire
Chris: What I have to do is I have to sell it right essentially to to someone like
Chris: You know any institution that takes USDC as an example, right and they will sell it on my behalf and give me a dollar
Chris: But you know if you sell like all of these institutions have
Chris: Fees for selling over a certain volume because obviously they want more in circulation because it's profitable
Chris: So you you don't always get a dollar back, you know, there are there are fees attached
Jackson: And if the
Tyler: Are there any big like third-party market makers that that do this like just operate a trading desk and they just make markets between all
Tyler: the stables and they have
Tyler: you know mint and burn on all the big stables and they just try to
Chris: Arbitrage everything like that. I think there's there's two things here. One is like
Chris: Makers that have access to every mint and burn and the other one is just makers who are playing what's called the sex decks
Chris: Arbitrage as in centralized exchange decentralized exchange arbitrage, right?
Chris: So, yeah, the answer is yes, there are big ones like I think winter mute plays in this space
Chris: I think like a lot of the other mainline big market makers do this arbitrage and especially those who have good relationships with the decks
Chris: but there are also like
Chris: there are like home operators who
Chris: Like do a lot of volume here, right? Like especially with the longer tail of venues
Chris: So like we're talking about like BNB Tron
Chris: These like chains that like, you know, not many people use and there is venue risk to them
Chris: Yeah, there are there are very small firms that that really
Chris: Contribute to a lot of that volume and I think like in that way, you know
Chris: This the unchained scene is still like very democratic. Like there are a lot of small players who are very sophisticated
Jackson: It has less technical question, but like as a user when I was sending you the the USDC so we could
Jackson: Degen it and a purple fortune, you know, I had to like select the the chain that I'm sending the USDC on
Jackson: And since I was able to select the chain that suggests that who at like the the partner the product that I'm using
Chris: Has USDC on all the chains that I can send it on
Jackson: but how does
Jackson: How do we make it simpler for a user to send?
Jackson: USDC or USDT to like their friend
Jackson: Without need to know what chain it's on like if I if you give me an ethereum address and
Jackson: I send you USDC on a
Jackson: Arbitrum unknowingly. It's gone, right?
Chris: Yeah, well, I mean so that
Chris: With the EVM chains
Chris: The good thing is like you still if you have that key like you still can get it right only your key can sign for
Chris: An address and the address is consistent across the chains
Chris: But like in turn they don't use different derivation paths or chin. I know I mean like like thankfully not right
Chris: That's a thankfully not. Well, I'm so there's there are like protections against accidentally broad like signing a transaction for one chain versus another
Chris: So it can't be replayed
Chris: But like your actual address derivation is, you know, generally the same across all of the the EVM chains
Chris: which at least like gives you some leeway to like
Chris: Obviate that issue, but I think like that issue shouldn't exist, right? It's like so confusing and it's so bad
Chris: the fragmentation of ecosystems that like
Chris: Kind of like your choice is either to like cop it on the chin and like your users lose funds or just like try and support
Chris: Everything right and I neither of those are like fantastic. I don't know Tyler if you
Chris: Probably have some like really sharp pointy feelings about this
Tyler: Not that much I mean I haven't
Tyler: Played in the altcoin space that much to like have a good opinion on this
Tyler: But I do think that it probably comes down to some kind of human readable address
Tyler: Standard that works across chains and coins
Tyler: Like there are various
Tyler: protocols that have been suggested where you could have like
Tyler: chris at
Tyler: permanent under pod comm and then I would send you know my USDC to that human readable address and then under the hood my
Chris: Wallet is looking up. Okay, given that address
Chris: Let me look up Chris's listing of like what his addresses are on various chains
Tyler: And maybe you've like rank ordered those in terms of your preference and then me as a sender
Tyler: I have like a you know various coins that I could spend I have my own preference and there's like protocols to
Tyler: Figure out what like the these common denominator is between the two of us and then descended along that
Tyler: I think something like that would solve the problem. But the issue is that like
Tyler: In order to have that kind of solution in the marketplace
Tyler: you just need like very broad adoption by a bunch of wallets by a different but bunch of
Tyler: Ecosystems coins chains, etc and bootstrapping that across all of those different players is like
Tyler: Extremely difficult if not impossible. So I think that like there are things
Tyler: Technologies out there that could go a long way towards solving that
Tyler: But I think it's more of a coordination problem than a technical problem
Chris: Yeah, I totally agree. I think like this is a
Chris: like a classic standards issue where like and like you see this in the EVM world where there's like various different ways to
Chris: Specify which chain you want to send to and everyone uses a different one. It's like it's a total mess
Chris: yeah, hopefully someone comes along and
Chris: creates the
Chris: Well adopted final standard, but I I don't think it's promising. Yeah, you can use like an ENS name to
Tyler: Host addresses for other chains to write like you say that anymore
Chris: Chris not you know, you can't say it's over. Yes is over. Did you not hear about this? I
Chris: Didn't did they get yeah, they got they got canceled. They they got they they got it done. The Dow was a sham
Chris: Shocked to everyone shocked everyone
Tyler: Yeah, Dow's are so robust and resilient and proven. What are you talking about?
Chris: So ENS is off the table and maybe Dow's forever. I don't know. It's a good question
Tyler: All those dot eats that I bought are worthless now. Is that what you're talking about?
Chris: You'll have to send them to the ENS graveyard
Tyler: Or should I go buy a bunch of ENS?
Tyler: Like at fire sale prices and bank on them coming back like crypto punks
Chris: You know, I think the cool thing to do now is fork ENS and give it another cool extension like that way
Chris: Mmm, maybe dot on the pod, you know in the works. Yeah, should we get our own?
Jackson: TLD so on the like making it easier for people to send it
Jackson: Could like a wallet offer like coinbase
Jackson: Since you were saying that the same address could be derived for all chains under the EVM
Jackson: Could they just do like a revolver thing where they catch it for you and just put it in the right place?
Jackson: And then they kind of put it on the chain
Jackson: They want it to be on and then from like a USDT versus USDC point of view
Jackson: They could just swap it to the asset that they want it to be on
Chris: totally, I would like I would say like there is a
Chris: Engineer here who maybe like would do something like that hypothetically
Chris: Yeah, I think I think like, you know, that's a
Chris: Standout architecture. I think that's how a lot of people are doing it
Chris: I think you know, the problem is always that like
Chris: Especially when you're going between stables, it's not always equivalent, right?
Chris: It's not always equivalent value and then like how do you communicate that to the user?
Chris: Or how do you make it up to them is always the big question
Chris: Like if I'm expecting a dollar from Jackson and I get a dollar minus two micro cents
Chris: It doesn't matter to me, but it feels weird to get 99 cents, right? Yeah
Tyler: Also, you're like committed to supporting every EVM chain if you're just like this works for all EVM then it's like what about my
Tyler: You know fork of Ethereum. Yeah, that gives me all of the supply. Yeah, Queen base. I said to you
Chris: See on my personal fork
Chris: Support that so that I can then trade it in. Yeah, I see that's a good idea
Jackson: And then like yeah, then there's like other chain, you know
Jackson: Non EVM chains like Solana unless you could derive an address on the Solana and the bat was like secure on your
Jackson: ethereum
Jackson: EVM address
Jackson: like the
Jackson: different I
Jackson: Guess their ones makes that challenging. Is that right? Yeah. Okay. Yeah a hundred percent and then you say I
Chris: Sorry, I think Claude is like losing its mind
Chris: With type of fortune, but hopefully it comes online soon
Chris: But I think like computers being throttled really badly so I get the sense of that too
Jackson: so you're talking about like, okay, you get the point nine nine nine nine nine and
Jackson: Like you don't want to lose that as the company that's hosting the wallet for the customer
Jackson: But does it ever deep egg up? So like would it just balance out in the long term or as a business?
Jackson: Could you like arbitrage them in some way? So then you even maybe come out ahead
Jackson: So then you can absorb the fees even better
Chris: Yeah, so normally when it deep eggs up that means something has broken badly I see right so that the deep egg up case is normally
Chris: like we're like some big institution has
Chris: Been obliterated and everyone's trying to rotate out of this asset and they're rotating into stables and the demand for stables is
Chris: Higher than they can be minted the rate at which they can be minted at and the the stable trades up
Chris: Right. So people like I'm willing to pay
Chris: One dollar and five cents on the dollar to get out of this terrible position with no liquidity
Chris: So yeah, if you see if you see a stable coin go above peg
Chris: Someone is having a terrible day. Maybe not you but so I see so you're saying that you wouldn't end up breaking even in the long
Jackson: Term, you'd always end up paying for the most part because normally the deep eggs are down
Jackson: So exactly like you would end up paying way more. Okay, that's cool. Now we now we now
Jackson: That's cool. Now we now we now
Jackson: All right, we shall transition to something else
Jackson: Which of the topics is interesting to you guys Chris. Do you need to tend to our purple fortune?
Chris: I'm
Chris: Typing into my split keyboard at light speed at Claude, but he I think he's having a terrible day himself. Okay
Tyler: turning gamer thumb to 11
Tyler: Do you feel like Claude is just saying like the only winning moves not to play
Chris: Yeah, I think he's I think he's sick of me to be honest with you
Tyler: perp of misfortune
Chris: Well, I mean seeing as we talked about ENS
Chris: Doing the dirty which is also Dow
Chris: Maybe we can talk about the bonk Dow. I think they're calling it an attack, but is a bonk down
Chris: So Dallas stands for decentralized autonomous or autonomous organization, what is that you ask? I don't know
Chris: That's my honest answer at this point. I don't know Tyler if you they are neither decentralized nor autonomous
Tyler: organizations
Chris: They are none of the above right and and that I think like there's there have been rulings that imply that they're not even really like
Chris: regulatory arbitrage anymore like
Chris: That sometimes they just treated like as individuals or as corporations like there's just no point
Chris: anyway
Chris: So
Chris: Bonk Dow is the Dow for famous coin doge bonk. Some of you may have heard of I didn't realize this
Chris: But it's market cap is still like whoa perp. We got a perp. We got a perp
Chris: Okay, let's go. We aren't already on the water
Chris: Only three cents, okay. All right
Chris: Yeah, anyway, so I didn't realize this but there's still like
Chris: Hundreds of millions of dollars of liquidity in doge bonk somehow
Chris: And the Dow had you know a war chest of worth 22 million dollars denominated in doge bonk, of course
Chris: and and the thing with this Dow is like
Chris: You know, it's it's set up but like not in like a very serious way and it has like governance weight
Chris: weight weighted voting so like you make these governance proposals in like their governance forum and
Chris: You vote based on how many doge bonk tokens you hold
Chris: And the problem with this particular one is the threshold for passing a vote
Chris: I think was like 1% of the supply. So if 1% of people vote on something
Chris: It goes through and somebody made this this proposal called
Chris: sorry, let me get this right because I think you'll really appreciate how insane this was a
Tyler: 1% threshold for the Dow to execute something. Yeah, I'm pretty sure it's a 1 1% threshold
Chris: Let me just check my notes, how did they get 20 million dollars in their treasury like who
Tyler: How did they accumulate this capital to start with and how wasn't it rugged immediately with a 1% threshold
Chris: yeah, so it's denominated in Bonk for starters, and I think like this this gets into like
Chris: Like like everyone involved in this is extremely stupid, okay
Chris: So so the treasury denominated in Bonk, right it this person makes a proposal called I think it's like
Chris: Sowelian Bonk proposal or something like after like Thomas Sowell who is like an economist a free-market economist
Chris: Who says that like, you know incentives over like intentions is kind of his big thing
Chris: and it has like all these Dow words in it and it's like we're gonna like
Chris: redistribute and rise from the ashes and
Chris: The the actual like physical like literal proposal of the Dow was send the whole treasury to my
Chris: to my wallet address
Chris: like I'm not making this up and so this guy who makes his proposal goes to buy bit and
Chris: And by Nance and buys 1% of the supply for 4.3 million dollars
Chris: Votes on his own proposal with I think it's like seven wallets with all this bonk in it
Chris: Gets it through and because it's like there's no time locks on this
Chris: There's no like counter punch the second the proposal goes through with only him voting. Yes on it
Chris: He just transfers to try the treasury to his own wallet
Jackson: And that was he able to wait exit with USD
Chris: Well, I mean this is the thing right like if if the price of doge bonk is contingent on the Dow being operational
Chris: like who is the marginal
Chris: Who is the marginal buyer for 20 million dollars in hacked doge bonk?
Chris: Like where's the who's buying maybe he was able to sell it before people found out
Chris: He sold a hundred eighty eight thousand dollars worth and he's 4.3 million in the hole to execute
Jackson: Oh, I didn't realize that so you actually lost money. Yeah
Chris: Well, I mean if he can sell then like maybe he can break even here to someone
Chris: But like I mean this wallet has to be blacklisted by every exchange at this point
Tyler: But also like he would just tank the price of the asset by selling 20 million of it in one thing like I
Tyler: Feel like this person was aware that this was a completely
Tyler: Like futile effort, but they're just doing it for like the art of it. It's like it it like a
Tyler: You know like a live art project
Jackson: You think that's why you did it
Chris: Or she it has to it has to be love of the game love of the game. Exactly. Yeah
Tyler: Yeah, cuz there's no way that you could spend four million dollars to acquire 1% of the supply. Okay, so then that implies
Tyler: 400 million dollar market cap and then I guess you're selling 20 million of that. So that's
Tyler: Yeah, I don't know 5%
Tyler: So maybe selling 5% of it wouldn't kill it entirely
Tyler: but then like Chris is saying there's the whole thing around like okay, if you've just
Tyler: Destroyed this ecosystem that obviously the value is gonna not hold
Chris: But yeah, it's it's like it's it's an insane thing to do
Jackson: So are the coins traceable like Bitcoin?
Jackson: Like if I transit if he transfers it to like a hundred other wallets, could he then get them back onto exchanges?
Chris: So yeah, I think like it's on Solana as an SPL token like there are ways out of it
Chris: But at some point like you need to get out of bonk
Chris: It's it's denominated in bonk like and you need to swap that bonk to someone to make it into something that like is fungible and
Chris: acceptable in my various places, so
Chris: Yeah, so I don't know where you go for AI made this
Jackson: Segment idea of the bonk down and I didn't really read it. But oddly enough bonk is the
Jackson: The crypto I've made the most money on and like I sent my taxes to my tax guy
Jackson: But it only had the cell because I moved it from coinbase for Robin Hood to get 3%
Jackson: Bonus or something. So like I he only had the sell side of the trade and he was like, how much did you buy?
Chris: 22,000 bonk for
Chris: Like I feel like an idiot
Tyler: Getting asked that from my tax guy is your tax guy of pod subscriber. I mean listener
Tyler: Can we just shout out Jackson's tax guy obviously listening right now now?
Tyler: You don't have to fill him in on your antics. He's gonna just know your losses based on perp of fortune
Jackson: Yeah, oh yeah, I hope perp of fortune is in taxable but
Jackson: Another funny thing that totally randomly happened my tax guy
Jackson: Changed and it became this guy who used to beat me in junior tennis
Jackson: So I said you like called me last year and I'm like, it's you know, I say his last name
Jackson: I'm not gonna say here. I'm like, dude that unis like Jackson
Jackson: And I'm like you still play anyway, but that me and my tax guy often good times
Chris: That's crazy yeah, I mean
Chris: I mean hopefully he owes you a favor because it sounds like you have a complicated tax situation
Chris: After this 20 million dollar doge luckily, I'm out of box
Jackson: No, so no skin in the game
Chris: Yeah, but yeah, I think like
Chris: What one of the big upshots of this is like a
Chris: Like AI is making it really easy to identify these opportunities
Chris: Be like as I think one of our mutual friends who maybe one day will come on this podcast will opine
Chris: Like there's still billions of dollars of liquidity in these random shit coins that like no one is using that have zero liquidity, right?
Chris: So like, you know, maybe we can go lower
Chris: and see
Chris: like
Chris: Maybe the time of the Dow is over. I don't know. It's a big call. That's very contrarian, but ooh
Jackson: We did say that we could do a contrarian take from you good contrarian take Chris. We're at okay
Jackson: well
Jackson: Yeah, I think we could still we could still conclude it. We'll have a shorter pod this week
Jackson: But yeah, hopefully we can edit this one correctly with all the different mishaps with the stupid quick time
Jackson: The HD and Tyler I don't know how yours stopped. It's not a second time, too
Tyler: So I have I'm gonna have three months of quick times and that the last two aren't synced, dude
Jackson: Why just stopped?
Chris: How did you even know it's over for the pod it was I
Chris: Think we need I think we need pod software. I actually like think well, let's see how this go. It might go. Well trust
Tyler: I love that we're building open to Yolo a hundred dollars and a perp of fortune every week
Tyler: But we're not willing to spend like $10
Chris: for monthly subscription
Chris: One of those things is that's true
Chris: Which one is a fortune money goes to zero I
Chris: Mean we're up one. Yeah, dude, right? This is a dog really exciting enough, dude
Tyler: That's the best of the best we should have honestly we should have perped into bonk. That was a huge huge miss
Tyler: I feel like your community is gonna rally around this on the
Tyler: Hacker and like I want this hacker to be the you know, the king of the bonk Dow and I'm gonna invest in it
Chris: The one thing that I read is that he's put the funds into something
Chris: down to power so I don't know if this is like I
Chris: Know if this is a genuine like Swellian operator as he might call himself or like what the deal is
Jackson: He's seeding bonk 2.0 with the plunderings of bonk 1.0
Tyler: Next level
Jackson: Well, what do you want to tell our viewers? We're gonna watch your talk about next week throw something down anything Tyler Chris
Tyler: I mean whatever is gonna happen in the news and between the you know in the next week. We got to stay fresh
Tyler: Maybe MEV I really want to know MEV was something that you would pitched earlier
Jackson: Yeah, me be
Jackson: We we still need to talk about agentic payments. I think that's something we should talk about. It's important
Jackson: Alright if the recording is stopping we're done. Alright, good job everybody. See you later
Jackson: Dude I'm gonna get so throttled by fable. I don't even think I can use it. I'll probably have to use Opus